# **Michael Remy**

Redmond, WA • 253 306 1380 • michaeldremy@gmail.com

Links: Portfolio | Github

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/michaeldremy/

#### **PROFESSIONAL PROFILE**

Full Stack Developer that has transitioned from technology sales. I am committed to creating optimized back-ends and mobile responsive front-end websites. I have experience working with RESTful APIs, writing unit tests for webpages and creating complex CRUD applications including e-commerce websites. The stacks I know are Python/Django, C#/ASP.NET, React Native and MERN (MongoDB, Express, React, NodeJS).

#### **SKILLS**

Programming Languages: Python, JavaScript, C#, HTML/CSS, Bootstrap, MySQL

**Technologies:** React, React Native, Redux, Django, Formik, Yup, Expo, ASP.NET, JWT (JSON Web Token), Postman, SQLite, Visual Studio Code, Android Studio, Github, Diffmerge, Material-UI, Ant Design, NodeJS, Express, MongoDB, MongoDB Atlas, ChartJt, ChartJS, RESTful APIs, AWS (Amazon Web Services), Auth0, Unity, Alan AI

**Other skills:** Project Management, Technology Sales, Leadership Development, Communicative, Collaborative, Problem Solving, Growth Mindset, Team Lead, Ambitious

### **PROJECTS**

<u>Voice News</u> | <u>Github</u> 09/2020 - 10/2020

Technologies Used: React, HTML/CSS, JavaScript, Alan Al

- Application that allows the user to search for the latest news only using their voice
- Integrated an AI called "Alan AI" which allows for the ability to add voice assistant to applications, Alan AI was used to call on a news API which returned a JSON object and then was saved into React state then got destructured through reusable React components
- Programmed Alan AI to read the latest news when searched by saying the specific terms and is able to open a specific article when using voice
- Designed all front end of application within React using HTML/CSS and JavaScript

Tweet Me | Github 05/2020 - 06/2020

Technologies Used: React, Python, Django REST Framework, HTML/CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, MySQL

- Created Twitter clone web application that allows users to sign up or login, create, like, comment, and retweet tweets
- Wrote unit tests and debugged in Python to ensure functionality for user sign up or login, tweet actions and RESTful API route calls worked under unique circumstances
- Integrated Django REST Framework to create RESTful API routing, handle user session, MySQL database for creating or logging in users, create, like, retweet, and delete tweets as well having users to follow other users
- Utilized React front-end framework to create Single Page Application, manage state for users across multiple pages and to create reusable components for front-end design

Covid-19 Tracker | Github 04/2020 - 05/2020

Technologies Used: MERN (MongoDB, Express, React and NodeJS), HTML/CSS3, ChartJS, Material-UI

- Individually created and deployed a completely responsive web application that pulls Covid-19 data from 100+ countries and present total recovered, infected and death cases
- Integrated real time JSON API through useEffect hook in React then made call-backs to database to save information using Node, Express and MongoDB
- Integrated ChartJS by using pulled information from JSON API to create data visual representation through deconstructed reusable React components with material-UI

Gym Bro | Github 02/2020 - 03/2020

**Technologies Used:** Python, Django, JavaScript, HTML/CSS3, MySQL, ChartIt, Bcrypt, Regex

• Collaborated as a group of four developers to create a website that allows users to login using Django/Python and select a daily workout. Users can keep track of their accomplishments and view a graphical representation of their workout statistics using ChartIt

- Implemented front and back-end validation utilizing HTML, JavaScript, Regex and Bcrypt for hashed passwords to enhance security
- Utilized MySQL database for its relational database so users can see their workout stats displayed through ChartIt on their profile page
- Took initiative to create all the front-end design, RESTful routing, set up Django models that allowed users to login or create an account and I assisted in the setup of the weekly list of workout models

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Freelancing Upwork	10/2020 – Present
Inbound Sales Associate & Customer Service USCutter (Redmond, USA)	03/2019 - 02/2020
Project Manager Fastsigns (Kirkland, USA)	03/2018 - 03/2019
Account Executive Datasphere Technologies Inc (Bellevue, USA)	10/2017 - 03/2018
Sales Representative/Team Lead Mobile One LLC (Bothell, USA)	03/2017 – 10/2017

# **EDUCATION**

Full Stack Web Development 02/2020– 05/2020

Coding Dojo, Bellevue, USA

Completed three full stack web development stacks: Python/Django, C#, ASP.NET and MERN (MongoDB, Express, React, Node)